A Guide to the Linton Massey-William Faulkner Collection
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Linton Massey-William Faulkner Collection 1923-1961
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6271
4 and half shelf feet
Linton Massey
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the Library's microfilms of the William Faulkner manuscripts in its custody; the microfilm may be consulted by any interested party, and it will be lent through the interlibrary loan system. Materials are constantly added. Long-term loans may be arranged. Use of the microfilm will be restricted to the premises of the borrowing library. No loans will be made to individuals. Researchers should enquire of the Manuscripts Division concerning availability of microfilm of manuscripts that are pertinent to their work. Most of the literary manuscripts in our collections written by Faulkner, both holograph and typescript, have also been published in facsimile in William Faulkner Manuscripts, 25 vols. (New York: Garland, 1986-87).
By the terms of the agreement by which the William Faulkner Foundation transferred the original manuscripts to the University, access to the original manuscripts is restricted (to ensure the survival of the physically-delicate originals) to doctoral candidates at the dissertation stage of their programs, and to certain mature scholars and critics. But even these researchers must demonstrate need to see the originals that goes beyond the requirements of most routine research. A doctoral candidate at the dissertation stage, or other qualified researcher who believes that his or her work requires access to the originals must correspond with the Curator of Manuscripts prior to arrival at the Library to obtain permission for access.
No microfilm, electrostatic, or other types of copies may be made of materials written by William Faulkner that are in our William Faulkner Collections. Other materials in the collections may be copied subject to the normal rules of the Library established under the conditions of the Copyright Act. All copying is performed by the Printing Services Department of the University.
Acquisition Information
A gift of Mr. Massey on 9 April 1960
Scope and Content
The Linton Reynolds Massey-William Faulkner Collection contains letters, manuscripts, films, recordings, and other Faulkneriana representing all areas and periods of the author's career; Faulkner family papers, and correspondence and manuscript materials of Linton Massey are also included. Holograph and typescript items include short stories, screenplays, speeches, letters, and the first page of Twilight (The Sound and the Fury). The collection fills seven Hollinger storage boxes and two maroon slipcases, or about four and one half shelf feet.
Additions have been made to this collection by other donors. That information is indicated in the description.
Arrangement
The listing is arranged in ascending numerical order by accession number. Items within each accession number are arranged with the convenience of the researcher in mind--some in strict chronological order, some separated into categories and then chronologically listed. The order of the listing follows the order of arrangement in the storage boxes to expedite the search for materials.
Container List
- Correspondence
  - William Faulkner to The Four Seas Co., w/TL (carbon) 1923 June 26, The Four Seas Co.to William Faulkner, 1 p. on 1 l., 1923 June 20; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - William Faulkner to the Four Seas Co., w/TL (carbon) 1923 Nov 13, The Four Seas Co.to William Faulkner, 1 p. on 1 l., TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - William Faulkner to the Four Seas Co., 1923 Nov 23; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - William Faulkner to the Four Seas Co., & 1 p. carbon of reply, 1924 July 22, 1 p. on 1 l., 1924 July 19; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - The Four Seas Co., to William Faulkner, 1924 Aug 4, 6, 11; 3 TL, 3 p. on 3 l.
  - William Faulkner to the Four Seas Co.., w/auto-biographical sketch 1 p. on 1 l. & 2 photos., 1924 Sep 9; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Bill [Faulkner] to Ben [Wasson], 1932 [Jan 26]; ALS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Bill [Faulkner] to Ben [Wasson], 1932 Sep 25; ALS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Bill [Faulkner] to Ben [Wasson]w/6 line holograph note, [1933]; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Bill [Faulkner] to [Ben Wasson], [1933 Jun 27]; ALS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - William Faulkner to Morty [Goldman], 1935 Feb 18; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - William Faulkner to Morty [Goldman]w/holograph note, 1935 Mar 9; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - William Faulkner to Morty [Goldman], [1935?]; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Bill [Faulkner] to Morty [Goldman], 1936 Sep 4; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Bill [Faulkner] to Morty [Goldman], [1936] Dec 28; ANS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Bill [Faulkner] to Morty [Goldman], 1937 Jan 21; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Bill [Faulkner] to Morty [Goldman] w/autograph postscript, 1938 Feb 19; TLS, 2 p. on 2 l.
  - Phillip C. Duschnes to Linton Massey, w/invoice, 1954 Mar 12; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - House of Books, Ltd.to Linton Massey, w/bill, dated 1954 April, 1954 Apr 20; TLS, 3 p. on 3 l.
  - "There Was A Queen", n. d.; AMs & photocopies, 5 p. on 5 l.
  - Phillip C. Duschnesto Linton R. Massey, 1954 Apr 22; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Phillip C. Duschnesto Linton R. Massey, 1954 Apr 26; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Phillip C. Duschnesto Linton R. Massey, 1954 May 6; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Invoice for "There Was A Queen", 1954 Apr 26; Invoice, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Phillip C. Duschnesto Linton R. Massey, with invoice, dated 1958 Mar 28, for "Idyll in the Desert," 1 p. on 1 l., 1958 Mar 25; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - William Faulkner to Cher Maitre [ Linton Massey], w/env., [1959 Jul 3]; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Jim [Meriwether?] to John [S. Van E. Kohn], 1960 Feb 25; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Fredson Bowersto Mr. [William] Faulknerw/holograph notation by Faulkner, 1961 Sep 29; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Fredson [Bowers] to Linton [Massey], [1961] Oct 4; ANS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Bill F[aulkner] to Morty [Goldman], Jul 24; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Faulkner to Morty [Goldman], Jul 29; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Faulkner to Morty [Goldman], Dec 4; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Faulkner to Morty [Goldman], w/AN, Inquiring about market for his autograph manuscripts of The Sound and Fury, etc. Working on novel., TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Faulkner to Morty [Goldman], enclosing rewritten Drusilla story, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - "faulkner" to Morty [Goldman], w/AN, "I'll leave this to your judgement." Sending another story for Post, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Faulkner to Morty [Goldman], sending short story. "Maybe this one will hit Cosmo", TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Faulkner to Morty [Goldman], "Enclosed. I would like for Dashiell at Scribner's to see this.. .", n. d.; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - "faulkner" to Morty [Goldman], altered story for Post. Rewriting Courage for novel, n. d.; TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Faulkner to Morty [Goldman], sending "Bear Hunt" to the Post, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - F[aulkner] to Morty [Goldman], "The enclosed is O. K. with me.. .", n. d.; ANS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Faulkner to Morty [Goldman], Re "Bear Hunt", n. d.; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Faulkner to Morty [Goldman], Re "Black Music", n. d.; TLS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Faulkner to Morty [Goldman], mentioning "Fool About a Horse" and "The Brooch", TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - "Bill F."[aulkner] to Morty [Goldman], to work on series of Reconstruction stories, n. d.; TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - [Faulkner] to Morty [Goldman], negotiations with Post for series, n. d.; TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Bill [Faulkner] to Ben [Wasson], concerning the use of colored inks for The Sound and the Fury, ALS, 2 p. on 2 l.
  - Bill [Faulkner] to Ben [Wasson], Wasson's coming home. Sending story to Harper's, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Bill [Faulkner] to Ben [Wasson], "The mss. goes to you today by express", n. d.; ALS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Bill [Faulkner] to Ben [Wasson], "Here is what I received re Cape & Smith.. .", n. d.; ANS, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - Bill [Faulkner] to Ben [Wasson], revision of proof. Explanation of story concerning agnostic, n. d.; TL, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - [William] F.[aulkner] to [Ben Wasson?], ends: "Just what did they want, if you remember?", ANS, 1 p. on 1 l.
- Manuscripts
  - Idyll In The Desert, w/auto. corrections, n. d.; TMs
  - "Mississippi Hills: My Epitaph", 1924 Oct 17; TMs, 1 p. on 1 l., w/photocopy
  - "Shall I Recall This Tree, When I Am Old", 1924 Oct 18; TMs, 1 p. on 1 l., w/photocopy
- Miscellaneous
  - Contract for publication of The Marble Fawn, 1924 Aug 4; Contract
  - List of display titles partly in William Faulkner's hand, [1959 Jun 18]; List w/photocopy
  - Seven Gables Bookshopinvoice to Linton Massey, 1960 Mar 9; Invoice, 1 p. on 1 l.
  - List of William Faulkner's acquaintances who he believed might want pamphlets re: The Sound and The Fury, holograph, signed, "Bill", List, 1 p. on 1 l.